Guide to the Robert R. Wilson papers, 1936-2000.
Wilson, Robert R. papers, 1936-2000.
- Series II. Correspondence - General/Professional
  - Chang Wen-yu, to R.R.W., C. U., re previous cable (phone message) [tl, signed], 9/30/1983 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Chang Wen-yu, to R.R.W., C. U., re proposed visit [tls], 3/10/1983 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Chang Wen-yu, to R.R.W., C. U., re travel preparations [cable], 10/6/1983 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Chang Wen-yu, from R.R.W., C. U., re cancellation of trip (draft of cable) [al], 10/29/1983 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Chang Wen-yu, Academia Sinica, Peking, to R.R.W., C. U., re cancellation of trip [phc], 11/1/1983 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Chang Wen-yu, to R.R.W., C. U., re cancellation of trip and return of tickets [mailgram], 11/4/1983 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Chang Wen-yu, to R.R.W., C. U., letter in Chinese [als], n.d. (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Chang Wen-yu, Academia Sinica, Peking, to R.R.W., C. U., re New Year's greeting and upcoming Tokyo meeting [phc], 2/17/1984 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Chang Wen-yu, Academia Sinica, Peking, to R.R.W., C. U., re Tokyo meeting [tls], 3/27/1984 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Chang Wen-yu, Academia Sinica, Peking, from R.R.W., C. U., re upcoming Tokyo meeting [phc]; reply to 4/17/1984 letter [tls]; C. W. from R.R.W., 6/12/1984 [phc], 4/17/1984 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Chang Wen-yu, Academia Sinica, Peking, to R.R.W., C. U., re visit to China [phc], 9/18/1984 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - [Chang Wen-yu], re travel arrangements [phc], n.d. (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Chang Wen-yu, to R.R.W., C. U., re travel arrangements [mailgram], 10/5/1984 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Chang Wen-yu, Academia Sinica, Peking, from R.R.W., C. U., re travel arrangements [cable], 10/12/1984 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Chang Wen-yu, from R.R.W., re travel schedule (draft) [als], n.d. (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Chang Wen-yu, to R.R.W., re travel procedures [cable text], annotations [al], n.d. (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Chang Wen-yu, from R.R.W., re travel schedule (draft) [am], n.d. (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Chang Wen-yu, Beijing, from R.R.W., re travel schedule (draft) [al], 10/31/1984 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Chang Wen-yu, Academia Sinica, Peking, to R.R.W., C. U., re personal health [tls], 4/29/1986 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Chang Wen-yu letter of condolence to "Dearest Colleagues in China," from R.R.W., Ithaca [phc]; reply from Mrs. Chang, 1/15/1993 [als], 11/25/1992 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Chapman, Seville, to R.R.W., re "Proposed Research at Cornell For an Atomic Disaster" [als], 7/1950 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Chapman, Seville, Cornell Aeronautical Laboratory, from R.R.W., re writing an article [cc], 9/30/1950 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Chapou, Pierre-Frantz, American Foundation for the Protection of Tyre, to R.R.W., Columbia University, re excavation of Tyre [tls]; reply, n.d. (draft) [al], 1/9/1981 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Cheatham, W. Augustus, Loma Linda University Medical Center to R.R.W., Ithaca, in appreciation of assistance with development of Proton Therapy [tls], 8/16/1995 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Cherrington, Ben M., University of Denver, to R.R.W., Santa Fe, invitation to regional conference on atomic energy [tls]; reply, 12/4/1945 [cc], 11/30/1945 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Cherrington, Ben M., University of Denver, to R.R.W., Santa Fe, reply to 12/4/1945 letter [tls], 12/14/1945 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Chester, Geoffrey V., C. U., to R.R.W., C. U.: thanks for donation [tls], 8/13/1990 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Chicago Sun, Editor, from R.R.W., Los Alamos, re spectre of nuclear energy [cc], 9/28/1945 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Childs, D. S., M. D., Radiology, to R.R.W., Harvard University, re reprints of article [tls], 10/25/1946 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Chinowsky, Willy, Berkeley: Department of Physics, to R.R.W., re session on "Star Wars" at "Rochester" conference on campus [tls], 5/20/1986 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Christov, Ch., JINR, to R.R.W., National Accelerator Laboratory, re Tbilisi [tls], 9/1969 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Christy, R. F., CIT, Pasadena, "response to letter of January 9 by David Z. Robinson," re meson factory [cc], 2/3/1964 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Cima, Joyce W., C. U., to R.R.W., C. U., re title of Professor Emeritus [tls], 1/28/1980 (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Cisko, George, Villa Park, Illinois, to R.R.W., Ithaca, re work at Fermilab [tls], note [als]; thank you note to R.R.W., 8/9/1993 [als], 7/20/1993 (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Clark, Arnold, UCB, to R.R.W., Harvard University, re results of tests on the eddy current losses in a model of a rotating condenser disk [tls], 10/4/1946 (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Clark, D. D., [C. U.], to R.R.W., [C. U.], re Ward Laboratory [phc], 10/10/1990 (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Clarke, Eric D., "in charge of cyclotron," re blueprints of M.I.T. cyclotron chamber and dee assembly [tls] (no blueprints), n.d. (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Clayton, John M., General Radio Company, to R.R.W., Princeton University, re General Radio EXPERIMENTER [tls], 6/26/1941 (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Cliggott, Richard T., C. U. Council, to R.R.W., C. U., re participation in recent Chicago alumni meeting [tls], 2/4/1958 (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Cobb, Henry N., Pei, Cobb, Freed & Partners, Architects, to R.R.W., Ithaca, re model photograph for building, possibly AAAS [tls]; draft of reply, n.d.; H.N.C. to R.R.W., 11/3/1993 [tls], 5/20/1993 (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Cocconi, Giuseppe, CERN, from R.R.W., re staying at CERN, work at C. U., upcoming Rochester conference [cc], 1/27/1960 (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Cocconi, Vanna T., to Dr. Ralph Shutt, BNL, re visit to Brookhaven and comparison with activities at C. U. [cc], 5/22/1954 (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Cockcroft, J. D.: (R. M. Fishenden for J.D.C.), Atomic Energy Research Establishment, Harwell, U. K., to R.R.W., re upcoming meeting [ml], 8/9/1948 (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Cockcroft, J. D.: (R. M. Fishenden for J.D.C.), Atomic Energy Research Establishment, Harwell, U. K., to R.R.W., re plans for meeting September 5-9, 1950 [tls, am notes]; reply, 1/12/1950 [cc], 10/1949 (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Cockcroft, J. D.: (R. M. Fishenden for J.D.C.), Atomic Energy Research Establishment, Harwell, U. K., to R.R.W., re date change for meeting [tls]; reply, 3/16/1949 [cc], 11/25/1949 (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Coffin, C. T., University of Michigan, from R.R.W., re proposed run at Cornell synchrotron [cc], P.S. [als], 2/12/1963 (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Coffin, Harry Bigelow, McGraw-Hill, from R.R.W., possible sponsorship for Atomic Age World Cooperative by FAS [cc], 1/4/1946 (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Cohen, S. G., The Hebrew University, Jerusalem, to R.R.W., C. U., re upcoming visit to Ithaca and synchrotron [tls]; reply, 5/2/1956; S.G.C. to R.R.W., 5/5/1956, re visit [tls], 4/26/1956 (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Cohen, S. G., The Hebrew University, Jerusalem, to R.R.W., C. U., re synchrotron, upcoming visit to U. S. [tls], photographs [phc], 6/29/1958 (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Cohn, Alfred E., M. D., re Bush Report on how to administer research in the United States [phc], 12/18/1945 (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Colby, V. E., C. U., to Dean Kelly, C. U., re meeting of University Committee on the Arts [phc], 5/10/1965 (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Cole, F. T., UCB, to R.R.W., C. U., re 200 BeV group [tls], UCID-10188-X [phc], 7/29/1966 (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Cole, Frank, from R.R.W., re "Oh, Camelot!" [tl], enclosure [phc], n.d. [1994+] (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Cole, K. C., to R.R.W., Frank [Cole] writings [tls], 11/13/[n.y.] (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Cole, Sterling, House of Representatives, from C. P. Baker, H. A. Bethe, D. R. Corson, E. D. Courant, J. W. DeWire, R. P. Feynman, C. W. Gartlein, P. L. Harman, H. E. Howe, B. D. McDaniel, P. Morrison, C. C. Murdock, H. F. Newhaus, L. G. Parratt, J. S. Saby, L. P. Smith, R. L. Sproull, C. D. Swartz, D. H. Tomboulian, R.R.W., W. M. Woodward, re Dr. E. U. Condon case [cc, signed]; [cc, not signed]; reply, 3/17/1948 [tls], form letter from B. B. Hickenlooper [mc], 3/9/1948 (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Colgate, Stirling, to R.R.W., re experiment results [tls], 12/9/1951 (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Colgate, Stirling A., Los Alamos, to R.R.W., re survival techniques and laboratory activities [als], 11/18/1980 (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Colgate, Stirling A., to "Jane and Bob," re birthday gift of sculpture [als], 11/16/1984 (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Colgate, Stirling and Rosie, re science and life [phc], 12/26/1995 (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Colgate, Stirling and Rosie, to "Jane and Bob," re visit, continuing experiments [greeting card, signed], n.d. (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Colleagues, from R.R.W., C. U., re reports on recent Rochester conference [mc], list of colleagues [mc], 6/29/1960 (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Collier, Robert J., Yale University, to R.R.W., re abstract in Phys. Rev. 82 concerning Delbruck scattering [tls]; reply, 3/4/1952 [cc], 2/22/1952 (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Collins, George B., University of Rochester, from R.R.W., re meeting of faculties, James Allen at U. Chicago [cc]; reply, 9/30/1947 [tls]; note from L.P.S. to R.R.W. re Krebs trip [al], 7/11/1947 (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Collins, George, BNL, from R.R.W., re c-shaped magnets and coils to excite them [cc]; reply 8/5/1952 [tls]; reply, 8/27/1952 [tls], 7/23/1952 (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Collins, Sonia, from R.R.W., letter of condolence on death of Tom (draft) [al], 1/17/1996 (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Collins, Tom and Sonia, Anacortes, WA, from R.R.W., Ithaca, re health news, best wishes (copy) [tl], 1/22/1994 (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Collins, Tom and Sonia, Anacortes, WA, from R.R.W., re health, best wishes (draft) [als], Christmas 1995 (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Collins, Thomas: obituaries by Don Edwards [fax] and R.R.W. [pm], 1/23/1996 (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Collalto, Rambaldo di, Milan, to Professor Henry De Wolf Smyth, Princeton University, forwarded to R.R.W., re isotron (in Italian) [tls]; translation and note from Dr. Smyth's secretary [tl]; reply, 3/8/1960 [cc], 2/6/1960 (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Comar, C. L., C. U., from R.R.W., forwarding letter, re Tuskegee Institute [cc], 2/12/1963 (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Conant, J. B., Harvard University, to R.R.W., Harvard University, re appointment of Committee on Research in Nuclear Physics [tls], 1/16/1946 (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - Condon, E. U., National Bureau of Standards, to R.R.W., re talk at symposium [tls]; reply, 1/25/1951, "Studies at Cornell of the gamma ray production of mesons and their interactions" [cc], 12/28/1950 (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - Counseil Européen Pour La Recherche Nucleaire (CERN), re hotels in Geneva [mc], 9/10/1953 (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - Conversi, Marcello, Universita Degli Studi -- Roma, to R.R.W., C. U., re proctoring an exam for Dr. Borgia [tls], 10/2/1964 (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - Cook, Alice, to R.R.W., re University Committee on Lectures [tls]; note on recto: question about Blackett [am], 8/23/1960 (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - Cook, Alice H., C. U., to members of committee: agenda for 9/23/1960 meeting [tls], 9/16/1960 (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - Cook, Alice H., C. U., to listed members of University Committee on Lectures: Dean Hanson, R.R.W., Arthur Mizener, Ericl Blackall, Rudolph Schlesinger, Victor Reynolds, B. L. Rideout, re invitations to Raymond Aron, Senator Barry Goldwater, Senator Fulbright, and Lester Pearson [cc]; reply 10/11/1960 [cc], 10/3/1960 (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - Cook, Alice H., C. U., to Lecture Committee, re invitation to Foreign Minister Roa of Cuba [cc]; letter to Professor Dowd, from A.H.C., 11/10/1960 re conditions of invitation [thc], 11/15/1960 (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - Cook, Alice H., C. U., to Lecture Committee, re Prof. Bishop replying to invitation to deliver two lectures [tl]; Morris Bishop to A.H.C., 5/6/1961 [thc], 5/15/1961 (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - Cook, Alice H., C. U., from R.R.W., re Morris Bishop lectures [cc], 5/16/1961 (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - Cooksey, Donald, UCB, to R.R.W., Princeton University, re shipment [tls], 9/24/1940 (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - Cooksey, Donald, UCB, to R.R.W., Princeton University, re delay in shipment, progress in Berkeley [tls], 10/31/1940 (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - Cooksey, Donald, UCB, from R.R.W., Princeton University, re quartz insulators, "radio-isotope" charts (draft) [al]; reply, 10/10/1941 [tls], n.d. (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - Cooksey, Donald, UCB, to R.R.W., Los Alamos, re temporary badge and pass [tls], 12/27/1945 (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - Cooksey, Donald, UCB, from R.R.W., re red tape for getting proton-proton equipment shipped to Berkeley [cc, am], 1/18/1946 (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - Cooksey, Donald, UCB, to Captain R. L. Miller for R.R.W., re official request to ship equipment to Berkeley [cc], 2/4/1946 (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - Cooksey, Donald, UCB, to R.R.W., re interest in Ernest O. Lawrence [tls]; reply, 4/27/1959 [cc], 4/13/1959 (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - Cooksey, Donald, UCB, to R.R.W., C. U., re equipment needed in Berkeley for experiment, news [tls], 4/30/1959 (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - Cool, Rodney L., BNL, to R.R.W., C. U., re meeting of the Brookhaven High Energy Discussion Group [tls], 12/3/1963 (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - Cool, Rodney L., BNL, to R.R.W., C. U., re visiting appointment [tls], 2/24/1964 (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - Cool, Rodney L., BNL, to "Dear Colleague," re agenda for meeting of the Brookhaven High Energy Discussion Group [phc], 12/28/1965 (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - Cooney, J., AEC, from R.R.W., re reports on radiation effects in Japan [cc]; reply by Victoria K. Strauch for J. C., 5/24/1950 [tls], 5/19/1950 (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - Cooper, Daniel I., Nucleonics, to R.R.W., C. U., re postponement/ rejection of article "Fusion Power Reactor Uses Shock Wave in Gas" [tls]; reply asking to withdraw article, 5/23/1958 [cc]; review of article by G. Sargent Janes, AVCO Research Laboratory, 5/13/1958 [thc], 5/19/1958 (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - Cooper, Daniel I., Nucleonics, to R.R.W., C. U., re withdrawal of article [tls], 6/3/1958 (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - Cooper, Daniel I., International Science and Technology, to R.R.W., C. U., re possible interview [tls], 11/4/1964 (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - Cooper, Daniel I., International Science and Technology, to R.R.W., C. U., re scheduling and format of "conversation" [tls]; reply, 1/7/1965 [cc], 11/23/1964 (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - Cooper, Daniel I., International Science and Technology, to R.R.W., C. U., re setting time for interview and mentioning expectations [tls], 1/22/1965 (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - Cooper, Daniel I., International Science and Technology, to R.R.W., C. U., re procedures with completed interview [tls]; reply, 2/17/1965 [cc], 2/5/1965 (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - Cooper, Daniel I ., International Science and Technology, to R.R.W., C. U., re edited version of "interview-bullsession" [tls], 2/23/1965 (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - Cooper, Daniel I., International Science and Technology, to R.R.W., C. U., re transcript with R.R.W. editorial comments [tls]; reply [cc], [before 3/8/1965] (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - Corbally, John F., MacArthur Foundation, from R.R.W., Columbia University, re support for Frank Oppenheimer's Exploratorium [phc], 5/12/1981 (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Corben, Mulaika, Pittsburgh, to R.R.W., re meeting for surprise birthday dinner for Feynman at O'Donnell's, lab news [tls], P. S. [als]; reply, 4/16/1947 [cc], note from 1986 re dinner and ensuing bet [am], 3/26/1947 (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Corben, Mulaika, Pittsburgh, to R.R.W., re paying off bet [tls], certification of ownership of two shares in Desert Queen Mines [tms], 7/20/1947 (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Cornog, R., UCB, to R.R.W., Princeton University, re giving away university property, laboratory news, report on car, requests return of any Weston meters [tls (not signed in R. C.'s hand)], 9/12/1940 (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Cornog, R.A.A., UCB, to R.R.W., Princeton University, re shipment, car he bought, gossip, laboratory activities [tls] 2 shipping receipts [1 cc, 1 tm], 10/17/1940 (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Cornog, R., Arlington, VA, to R.R.W., re fellows, travel [als], 10/12/1941 (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Cornog, R., Arlington, VA, to R.R.W., Princeton University, re fellows, invitation to visit, information on sources for equipment [post card]; letter to R. C. from Bill Brobeck, UCB [tls], note to R.R.W. [als], 10/18/1941 (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Cornog, R., Arlington, VA, to R.R.W., re letter to Bill Brobeck re equipment [als], "Sunday night" (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Cornog, R., Princeton University, to R.R.W., re equipment assembly estimates [tl], 12/2/1942 (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Cornog, R., Princeton University, to R.R.W., re availability of electricians [tls]; R. C. to Stone & Webster Engineering Corporation, re moving the cyclotron [tl], calculations on verso [am], 1/9/1943 (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Cornog, R., Princeton University, from Professor P. W. Bridgman, Harvard University, re inventory of parts and removal of cyclotron [tls], 3/20/1943 (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Cornog, Robert, Harvard University, to Major B. K. Hough, Jr., Stone & Webster Engineering Corp., transmitting 2 copies of inventory, duplicate copies of construction photographs, and one copy of a letter of acknowledgment from Prof. P. W. Bridgman, Harvard University (signed E. M. Burke for Dr. Cornog) [tl], 3/20/1943 (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Cornog, R., Princeton University, to R.R.W., Santa Fe, re leaving Princeton (signed R. Cornog per Mm) [tl], 3/25/1943 (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Cornog, R., Princeton University, to Prof. P. W. Bridgman, Harvard University, re forwarding letter and inventories to R.R.W. [cc], 3/25/1943 (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Cornog, R., to R.R.W., Santa Fe, re current cyclotron situation, jobs for physicists, some personalities in labs [tls, al], P. S. [al], P.P.S. [al] note on verso [al], 10/2/1945 (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Cornog, Bob and Alice, to Jane and Bob and "Wilsons Three," re family and job news and security clearance status [tls], E. U. Condon from R. C., 7/2/1947 [cc], Commanding General, Air Material Command, from R. C. [cc], statement [cc], 7/30/1947 (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Cornog, R., to R.R.W., re request for character affidavits for security clearance hearing [mc, signed], P.S. [als], Harold A. Davenport to R. C. re appeal [mc], page of instructions [mc], 5/10/1949 (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Corrigan, K. E., The Harper Hospital, to R.R.W., C. U., re report on meeting regarding plans for the "Physical Handbook of Radiology" [tls], report [cc], 12/12/1951 (Box 1, Folder 76)
  - Corrigan, K. E., The Harper Hospital, from R.R.W., re outline of chapter for "Handbook of Radiology" [cc], outline [cc], 9/15/1952 (Box 1, Folder 76)
  - Corson, Dale R., UCB, to R.R.W., re news of travels and plans, advice on Princeton, cyclotrons he had seen [als], 5/5/1940 (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - Corson, Dale, C. U., to R.R.W., re recent visit [als], 12/9/1946 (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - Corson, Dale, to R.R.W., re job offer and visit to Pittsburgh [als], 8/1/[n.y.] (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - Corson, Dale, to R.R.W., re trip to Pittsburgh and decision on staying at C. U., current status of synchrotron [als], Thursday (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - Corson, Dale R., CIT, from R.R.W., re cyclotron news, good wishes [cc], 3/18/1954 (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - Corson, Dale R., Sebastopol, Ca., from R.R.W., C. U., re being Acting Director of Laboratory during his absence, lab news [cc]; reply in affirmative 7/22/1954 [als], 7/13/1954 (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - Corson, Dale R., C. U., from R.R.W., C. U., re duties of Acting Director of Laboratory [tls], annotations [al]; ["clean" cc], 8/24/1954 (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - Corson, Dale R., to D.V.Z. Peterson, CIT, re trip home, plates, thanks [cc], 9/8/1954 (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - Corson, Dale R., to R.R.W., École Normale Superieure, re trip to Ithaca, duties at the laboratory, status of plates from California [cc], 9/8/1954 (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - Corson, Dale R., to Professor L[loyd] P. Smith, Rockefeller Hall, re space for and planned use of cyclotron in Rockefeller Hall, equivalent space to be made available in Nuclear Lab [cc], 9/23/1954 (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - Corson, Dale R., to Dr. R. F. Bacher, CIT, re status of synchrotron, "pressure sensitive effect" [cc], 9/24/1954 (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - Corson, Dale R., to R.R.W., Ecole Normale Superieure, re laboratory personnel, operations, teaching load, equipment, recent hurricane [tls], annotations [al], ["clean" cc], 11/6/1954 (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - Corson, Dale R., to Dean Francis E. Mineka, C. U., re establishment of Graduate Laboratory of Solid State Physics [phc], 5/28/1959 (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - Corson, Dale R., C. U., to R.R.W., C. U., re appointment of Brobeck architect-engineer for 10 GEV machine [tls], 5/21/1964 (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - Corti, Adi Tongiorgi: R.R.W. to U.S. Immigration Service, re extension of visitor's visa [cc], 12/8/1949 (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - Coryell, Charles D., FAS, to R.R.W., Harvard University; W. R. Higinbotham, FAS; W. E. Cohn, A.O.R.E.S., Oak Ridge; B. Feld, MIT, A. H. Jaffey, Atomic Sci., R. Gehman, Amer. United for World Gov.: copies of letters to Jerry Voorhis, Representative 12th Congressional District; Hon. Chet Holifield, Representative 19th Congressional District; Hans Gaffron, University of Chicago, re thanks for assistance to atomic scientists (text of telegrams) [cc], 11/4/1946 (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - Coryell, Charles D., FAS, to Roger Babson, Babson's Reports, re FAS [cc], 11/16/1946 (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - Coryell, Charles D., ACS Portland Meeting, to R.R.W., The University, Birmingham, England, re "Un-American Committee" activities, U.N. General Assembly and a few tips on contacts in Paris circles [tls], P.S. [tl]; reply, 10/15/1948 [cc], 9/15/1948 (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - Cotterman, R. S., Minneapolis, to R.R.W., Princeton University, re request for autograph [als], 2/4/1946 (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - Cotton, Clare M., The Wall Street Journal, to R.R.W., C. U., re participation in luncheon-discussion session [tls]; thank-you 6/16/1956 [tls], 6/6/1956 (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - Cottrell, L. S., Jr., C. U., from R.R.W., re building equipment fund [cc], 3/9/1949 (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - Cottrell, L. S., Jr., C. U., from R.R.W., re Inter-University High Altitude Laboratory mentioned in 3/22/1949 letter from T. P. Wright [cc], 3/28/1949 (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - Cottrell, L. S., Jr., C. U., from R.R.W. (written by Roger Knox), re budget for 1949-1950 and future of C. U. nuclear studies program (draft, not sent) [tl], notes [al], 4/13/1949 (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - Cottrell, L. S., Jr., C. U., from R.R.W., re request for additional funding for nuclear studies [cc]; reply [tls], 5/26/1949 (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - Cottrell, L. S., Jr., C. U., from Lloyd P. Smith, re possible services which the Department of Physics, LNS, and the Department of Engineering Physics could render to business and industry [cc], 8/25/1949 (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - Cottrell, L. S., Jr., C. U., to "Chairmen of Departments," re budget requests for 1951-1952 [tls], 12/2/1950 (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - Cottrell, L. S., Jr., C. U., to "Department Chairmen," re letter to be considered when making budget requests [tls], enclosure: letter from President concerning probable effect of the international crisis on the University's enrollment and finances [mc], 12/11/1950 (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - Couch, William T., P. F. Collier & Son Corp., from R.R.W., re article on particle accelerators for encyclopedia (draft) [als]; W. T. C. from R.R.W., 6/25/1959 [tls]; W. T. C. to R.R.W., 7/9/1959; reply 8/7/1959 [cc], 6/3/1959 (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - Courant, Ernest D., BNL, to "Dear Friends": thank you for Fermi Award letters [tls], 12/29/1986 (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - Cousins, Norman, The Saturday Review, to R.R.W., re letter in Chicago Sun, request to write an article on danger of atomics [tls]; 11/12/1945, reply, and manuscript [cc]; N. C. to R.R.W., 11/19/1945 [tls], 10/15/1945 (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - Coutinho, Odete, Commisao Nacional de Energia Nuclear, to R.R.W., C. U., re request for copy of article [tls], 5/27/1988 (Box 1, Folder 78)